<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="gamescope_reshade">

  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2024 Wayne Heaney

    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
    copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
    to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
    the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
    and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
    Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including the next
    paragraph) shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the
    Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
    IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
    FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT.  IN NO EVENT SHALL
    THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
    LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
    FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER
    DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <description summary="gamescope-specific reshade integration">
    This protocol allows applications to load and interact with a reshade FX shader in gamescope.
  </description>

  <interface name="gamescope_reshade" version="1">
    <request name="destroy" type="destructor"></request>
    
    <request name="set_effect">
      <description summary="set the path to the reshade FX file">        
        The effect will be disabled to allow an opportunity to set uniform variables before enabling it.
      </description>
      <arg name="path" type="string" summary="Path to the FX file"></arg>
    </request>

    <event name="effect_ready">
      <description summary="alerts when the requested effect is ready">
        This event alerts the client when an effect has been enabled.
      </description>
      <arg name="effect_path" type="string" summary="Path to the FX file"/>
    </event>

    <request name="enable_effect">
      <description summary="turn on the effect">
        Enables the effect that was previously loaded by set_effect.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="set_uniform_variable">
      <description summary="set a uniform variable for the currently loaded effect">        
        Set the value of a uniform variable. Can be called before or after enabling the effect.
      </description>
      <arg name="key" type="string" summary="Name of the uniform variable"></arg>
      <arg name="value" type="array" summary="Value of the uniform variable"></arg>
    </request>

    <request name="disable_effect">
      <description summary="turn off the effect">
        Disables the effect that was previously enabled by enable_effect.
      </description>
    </request>
  </interface>
</protocol>
